Guide to the Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 4. Office Administration Files, 1962-2010 TJU.2010.01.04
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 4. Office Administration Files
1962-2010
ULS Archives & Special Collections
Specter, Arlen
TJU.2010.01.04
173.75 Linear Feet
The Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 4. Office Administration Files document administrative processes in Senator Specter's office. Specter served as U.S. Senator from 1981 to 2011, making him the longest-tenured Pennsylvanian senator. The group contains memos, manuals, telephone logs, itineraries, photos, reports, correspondence and schedules.
Custodial History
Material was transferred to the care of Philadelphia University in 2010-2011 from the Federal Records Storage Facility in Suitland, Maryland, as well as the Senator's Washington, D.C. and Pennsylvania offices. The physical material was transferred to the University of Pittsburgh in 2014, with the exception of selected photographic and memorabilia items that remain at the Arlen Specter Center's Roxboro House for display. In 2016, Philadelphia University merged with Thomas Jefferson University, and is now known as Thomas Jefferson University- East Falls campus.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Arlen Specter to Philadelphia University in 2010. Philadelphia University and the University of Pittsburgh entered into a partnership to jointly manage the collection in 2013.
Biography
Born in Wichita, Kansas, on February 12, 1930, Arlen Specter came to Pennsylvania to attend the University of Pennsylvania. He married Joan Levy in 1953, and graduated from Yale Law School in 1956. He became assistant district attorney in Philadelphia in 1959. In 1962, Specter was recommended to serve on the Warren Commission, assembled to investigate the assassination of President John F. Kennedy. As part of the Commission, he was responsible for co-authoring the proposal of the "single bullet theory," determining that one bullet struck both President Kennedy and Texas Governor John Connally. Specter ran for Philadelphia district attorney in 1965, switching his Party membership to Republican in order to unseat the incumbent Democrat. He was successful, and served as district attorney from 1966 to 1974.
After an initial failed run for Senator and then for Governor of Pennsylvania, Specter was elected to the U.S. Senate in 1980. He would stay in this position from 1981 to 2011, making him the longest-tenured senator in Pennsylvania's history. During this time, he was a member of a number of Committees: Judiciary (1981-2011; Chair, 2007-2007), Appropriations (1981-2011), Veterans Affairs (1981-2011; Chair, 1997-2001 and 2003-2005), Select Intelligence (1985-1991; 1995-1997; Chair, 1995-1997), Special Aging (1991-1995; 2007-2011), Governmental Affairs (1997-2001; 2003-2005), and Environment and Public Works (2001-2003; 2009-2011).
Though elected as a Republican, Specter was a moderate on many issues, including healthcare reform, immigration, and abortion. He would often cross party lines, such as in voting against the confirmation of President Ronald Reagan's nominee Judge Robert Bork to the Supreme Court in 1987. Specter would again come into the spotlight during a Supreme Court nomination process in 1991, for his cross-examination of Professor Anita Hill regarding her allegations against nominee Clarence Thomas. In 1999, he would vote against the charges brought against President Bill Clinton, giving an answer of "not proven" to reflect his belief that Clinton had not received a fair trial.
As Senator, Specter championed a number of causes and influenced many legislative areas. He was frequently a member of Congressional Delegation trips, particularly to the Middle East, where he would speak out on the cause of freedom from religious persecution and the importance of strong diplomatic relations. He was also a proponent of funding for medical research, including the use of stem cells. He advocated for strict crime laws, particularly for career criminals. His focus on benefitting Pennsylvania could be seen through the pursuit of grant funding opportunities and his attempt to prevent the closure of the Philadelphia Naval Shipyard in the 1990s.
With the worsening of Congressional partisanship in the late 2000s, Specter found himself frequently voting with his Democratic peers. After being one of only three handful of Republicans to vote for the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act in 2009, Specter found himself increasingly marginalized within his party. In April 2009, he returned to the Democratic Party, helping to ensure the passage of the Affordable Care Act. Seeking re-election in 2010, he was defeated in the Democratic primary by Joe Sestak.
Specter's 30-year tenure in the Senate concluded in January 2011. After leaving the Senate, he partnered with Philadelphia University (now Jefferson-East Falls) to establish the Arlen Specter Center for Public Service. In the fall of 2012, Specter, who had previously beaten Hodgkin's lymphoma in 2005 while serving as Chair of the Judiciary Committee, was diagnosed with cancer. He died on October 14, 2012, aged 82.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Arrangement
Group 4 is arranged into five series reflecting administrative processes in Senator Specter's office:
Series I. Administrative Assistant Files, 1962-2010
Series II. Memos, 1981-2010
Series III. Office Management, 1981-2001
Series IV. Telephone Logs, 1981-1986
Series V. Trip Files, 1981-2010
Scope and Content Notes
The Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 4. Office Administration Files comprises 140 boxes of material documenting administrative processes in Senator Specter's office. This includes documentation of the routine duties of office staff members through memos, files of individual office staff members, and policies and manuals. Also included in this group are administrative documents on the Senator's travel, both domestic and international. The group contains memos, manuals, telephone logs, itineraries, photos, reports, correspondence and schedules.
Related Material
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 1. Pre-Senatorial Career Files, 1953-1980, TJU.2010.01.01
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 2. Legislative Files, 1965-2011, TJU.2010.01.02
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 3. Personal, Political and Official Files, 1944-2010, TJU.2010.01.03
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 5. Constituent Services Files, 1976-2007, TJU.2010.01.05
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 6. Public Relations and Media Files, 1972-2010, TJU.2010.01.06
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 7. Campaign Files, 1976-2004, TJU.2010.01.07
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 8. Awards and Memorabilia, 1957-2010, TJU.2010.01.08
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 9. Photographs, 1930-2010, TJU.2010.01.09
Arlen Specter Senatorial Papers, Group 10. Electronic Records, 1980-2010, TJU.2010.01.10
Politicians; Correspondence; Cuba; Iraq; Taiwan; China; Pennsylvania; Travel; Memorandums; Politics; United States. Congress; United States. Congress. Senate; Specter, Arlen
- Administrative Assistant Files, 1962-2010; I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  Administrative Assistant Files contain the materials kept by 40 individual administrative employees in Senator Specter's office. Administrative employees, including directors, counsel, chiefs of staff, assistants and others, were responsible for a number of duties within the office. This included scheduling, providing legal assistance, human resources work, casework, and routine office management. When identified, job titles and dates of employment are indicated. Assistants are arranged alphabetically by last name, and alphabetically by topic within each subseries (excluding Lonnie Taylor, whose materials are arranged chronologically to reflect her filing system). The files contain memos, correspondence, schedules, invitations, and trip itineraries.
  - Charles Battaglia, 1984-1999; 1.
    Charles Battaglia worked in Senator Specter's office, with materials dated 1984-1999.
    - Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) address, 1996 (Box 574, Folder 1)
    - Congressional Delegation (CODEL), Iraq, India and Pakistan, January 1990 (Box 574, Folder 2)
    - CODEL, Pakistan, Saudi Arabia and Syria (revised), January 1990 (Box 574, Folder 3)
    - CODEL, USSR, January 1990 (Box 574, Folder 4)
    - CODEL, USSR, India, Iraq, January 1990 (Box 574, Folder 5)
    - CODEL, El Salvador, Panama and Chile, April 1990 (Box 574, Folder 6)
    - CODEL, Europe, August-September 1990 (Box 574, Folder 7)
    - CODEL, Belgium, Bulgaria, August-September, 1990 (Box 574, Folder 8)
    - CODEL, Portugal and Morocco, August-September 1990 (Box 574, Folder 9)
    - CODEL, South Africa, Kenya, Uganda, Central African Republic, Congo, Cameroon and Nigeria, April 1993 (Box 574, Folder 10)
    - CODEL, Moscow, October 1993 (Box 574, Folder 11)
    - CODEL, Bosnia (Patterns of Global Terrorism report), December 1998 (Box 574, Folder 12)
    - CODEL, Britain, Israel and Syria, December 1998 (Box 574, Folder 13)
    - CODEL, Egypt, Cyprus and Macedonia, December 1998 (Box 574, Folder 14)
    - Honduras torture, 1994-1995 (Box 574, Folder 15)
    - Intelligence chronological files, 1984-1985 (Box 574, Folder 16)
    - Intelligence chronological files, 1986 (Box 574, Folder 17)
    - Intelligence chronological files, 1987 (Box 575, Folder 1-2)
    - Intelligence chronological files, 1988 (Box 575, Folder 3-4)
    - Intelligence chronological files, 1989-1990 (Box 575, Folder 5)
    - Intelligence chronological files, 1991 (Box 575, Folder 6)
    - Intelligence chronological files, 1992 (Box 575, Folder 7-8)
    - Intelligence chronological files, 1993-1994 (Box 575, Folder 9)
    - Intelligence chronological files, 1995 (Box 575, Folder 10-12)
    - Intelligence chronological files, 1996 (Box 575, Folder 13-14)
    - International Criminal Court (ICC) (Box 575, Folder 15)
    - ICC, 1993-1997 (Box 575, Folder 16)
    - ICC, 1997 (Box 575, Folder 17)
    - ICC, 1998 (Box 575, Folder 18)
    - ICC, 1998 (Box 576, Folder 1)
    - ICC, 1999 (Box 576, Folder 2)
    - ICC, Specter legislation and statements, 1998 (Box 576, Folder 3)
    - Memos, 1996 (Box 576, Folder 4-6)
    - Notes, 1997 (Box 576, Folder 7-8)
    - Notes, 1998 (Box 576, Folder 9-10)
    - Phone records, 1997 (Box 576, Folder 11)
    - Phone records, 1998 (Box 576, Folder 12)
    - Travel information, Africa, 1993 (Box 576, Folder 13)
    - Travel information, Cyprus and Greece, 1988-1990 (Box 576, Folder 14)
    - Travel information, Nicaragua, Peru and Argentina, 1990 (Box 576, Folder 15)
    - Veterans, 1997-1998 (Box 576, Folder 16-17)
    - Weapons of Mass Destruction (WMD) Commission, 1996-1999 (Box 577, Folder 1)
  - Bill Bayer, 1985-2010; 2.
    Bill Bayer served as: community relations/veterans' affair coordinator, 2000-2006; and deputy director, Pittsburgh office, 2007-2010.
    - Congratulations letters, 2001-2010 (Box 577, Folder 2)
    - Dorothy Six, 1985 (Box 577, Folder 3)
    - Letters of support, 1998-2007 (Box 577, Folder 4)
    - Thank-you letters, 2002-2007 (Box 577, Folder 5)
  - Heather Blum, 2006-2007; 3.
    Heather Blum served as assistant to the chief of staff, 2007.
    - Staff memos, September 2006 (Box 577, Folder 6-7)
    - Staff memos, October 2006 (Box 577, Folder 8-9)
    - Staff memos, November 2006 (Box 577, Folder 10)
    - Staff memos, December 2006 (Box 577, Folder 11)
    - Staff memos, January 2007 (Box 577, Folder 12-14)
    - Staff memos, February 2007 (Box 578, Folder 1-2)
  - Scott Boos, 1987-2010; 4.
    Scott Boos served as: assistant to the chief of staff, 2002-2004; scheduler, 2004-2005; and staff assistant, 2006-2009.
    - Budget, 1996 (Box 578, Folder 3-5)
    - Budget, 1997 (Box 578, Folder 6-7)
    - Budget, 2000 (Box 578, Folder 8)
    - Budget, 2001 (Box 578, Folder 9-11)
    - Budget, 2002 (Box 578, Folder 12)
    - Budget, 2003 (Box 578, Folder 13)
    - Budget, 2004 (Box 578, Folder 14-15)
    - Budget, 2004 (Box 579, Folder 1-2)
    - Budget, 2005 (Box 579, Folder 3-4)
    - Budget reconciliation, 2006 (Box 579, Folder 5-6)
    - Budget reconciliation conference report, 2006 (Box 579, Folder 7)
    - Budget votes, 1997-2003 (Box 579, Folder 8)
    - Budget votes, 2003-2005 (Box 579, Folder 9)
    - Business constituent requests, 2003-2009 (Box 579, Folder 10)
    - Business and tax, 2003-2008 (Box 579, Folder 11)
    - Business and tax memos, 1996-1997 (Box 579, Folder 12-14)
    - Chronological files, December 2004 (Box 580, Folder 1)
    - Chronological files, January-February 2005 (Box 580, Folder 2)
    - Chronological files, March-April 2005 (Box 580, Folder 3)
    - Chronological files, May 2005 (Box 580, Folder 4)
    - Chronological files, June-July 2005 (Box 580, Folder 5)
    - Chronological files, July-September 2005 (Box 580, Folder 6)
    - Chronological files, September 2005 (Box 580, Folder 7)
    - Chronological files, October 2005 (Box 580, Folder 8)
    - Chronological files, November 2005 (Box 580, Folder 9)
    - Chronological files, December 2005 (Box 580, Folder 10)
    - Flat tax, 1999-2003 (Box 580, Folder 11)
    - Fortress Investment Group, 2009 (Box 580, Folder 12)
    - Hearings, 2006-2008 (Box 581, Folder 1)
    - Legislation, 1987-1999 (Box 581, Folder 2)
    - Legislation, 2002-2006 (Box 581, Folder 3)
    - Legislation, 2007 (Box 581, Folder 4)
    - Legislation, 2008 (Box 581, Folder 5)
    - Meetings, 1997-2004 (Box 581, Folder 6)
    - Meetings, 2007 (Box 581, Folder 7)
    - Meetings, 2007-2008 (Box 581, Folder 8)
    - Memos, 2007 (Box 581, Folder 9)
    - Memos, 2007-2008 (Box 581, Folder 10)
    - Memos, 2008-2009 (Box 581, Folder 11)
    - Memos, 2009-2010 (Box 581, Folder 12)
    - Regrets, 2005 (Box 581, Folder 13-14)
    - Social Security, Budget, 2006 (Box 582, Folder 1)
    - Social Security, Notch issues, 1991-1999 (Box 582, Folder 2-3)
    - Social Security, Reform, 2005 (Box 582, Folder 4)
    - Social Security, Voting record, 1998-1999 (Box 582, Folder 5)
    - Steel, American Iron and Steel Industries, 2005-2008 (Box 582, Folder 6)
    - Steel, Caucus, 2000-2004 (Box 582, Folder 7-8)
    - Steel, Internal Revenue Service (IRS) Section 29 steel tariff, 2004-2005 (Box 582, Folder 9-10)
    - Steel, International Trade Commission, 2001-2007 (Box 582, Folder 11-12)
    - Steel, Letters, 2002-2009 (Box 582, Folder 13-14)
    - Steel, Meetings, 2001-2009 (Box 582, Folder 15)
    - Steel, Section 201 steel tariffs, 2002-2004 (Box 582, Folder 16-17)
    - Steel, Specter actions, 2002-2005 (Box 583, Folder 1-2)
    - Steel, Tax credits, 2009-2010 (Box 583, Folder 3)
    - Steel, United Steel Workers, 2003-2005 (Box 583, Folder 4)
    - Taxes, American Recovery and Investment Act, 2009 (Box 583, Folder 5-6)
    - Trade letters, 2009 (Box 583, Folder 7)
    - Veterans, Community Based Outpatient Centers (CBOCs), Fayette, Venango, Warren, 2004-2005 (Box 583, Folder 8)
    - Veterans, CBOCs, Northamptons, Sunbury, 2003-2004 (Box 583, Folder 9)
    - Veterans, Environmental Assessment, Southeastern Pennsylvania cemetery, 2003-2007 (Box 583, Folder 10-14)
    - Veterans, Site announcement, 2005-2006 (Box 583, Folder 15-16)
  - David Brog, 1993-2004; 5.
    David Brog served as: counsel, 1997-2004; and chief of staff, 2004-2005.
    - 9/11, 2003 (Box 584, Folder 1)
    - 9/11 Fund, 2003 (Box 584, Folder 2)
    - Acts, 2003 (Box 584, Folder 3)
    - Agenda, 2003 (Box 584, Folder 4)
    - Alien Tort Claims Act, 2003 (Box 584, Folder 5-6)
    - Amish, 1998-2003 (Box 584, Folder 7)
    - Appearances, 2004 (Box 584, Folder 8)
    - Appropriations, 1996 (Box 584, Folder 9)
    - Appropriations, Simon Wiesenthal Center, 1995-1996 (Box 584, Folder 10)
    - Asbestos, 2003 (Box 584, Folder 11)
    - John Ashcroft, 2004 (Box 584, Folder 12)
    - Brog correspondence, 2004 (Box 584, Folder 13)
    - Business, 1999-2000 (Box 584, Folder 14)
    - Campaign funds, 2003 (Box 584, Folder 15)
    - Class Action Fairness Act, 2003 (Box 584, Folder 16-19)
    - Class action suits, 1998-2004 (Box 584, Folder 20)
    - Class action suits, 1998-2004 (Box 585, Folder 1)
    - Colombian ambassador meeting, 1999 (Box 585, Folder 2)
    - Congressional continuation, 2001 (Box 585, Folder 3)
    - Coordination, 2004 (Box 585, Folder 4)
    - Copyright, 1996-2004 (Box 585, Folder 5-6)
    - Constituent letters, April 1996 (Box 585, Folder 7)
    - Constituent letters, May 1996 (Box 585, Folder 8)
    - Constituent letters, June-July 1996 (Box 585, Folder 9)
    - Constituent letters, August-November 1996 (Box 585, Folder 10)
    - Constituent letters, 1999 (Box 585, Folder 11)
    - Counterfeiting (Box 585, Folder 12)
    - Darfur, 2004 (Box 585, Folder 13)
    - Department of Justice interviews, 2003 (Box 585, Folder 14)
    - DNA, 2003 (Box 585, Folder 15)
    - Drafts, 2004 (Box 585, Folder 16)
    - Economic Stimulus Act, 2004 (Box 585, Folder 17)
    - Elderly Holocaust survivors, 2003-2004 (Box 585, Folder 18)
    - Environment, 1996 (Box 585, Folder 19)
    - Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI), 2002-2004 (Box 585, Folder 20)
    - FBI oversight, 2003 (Box 585, Folder 21)
    - Federal Election Commission (FEC), 1998-1999 (Box 585, Folder 22)
    - Fourteenth Amendment, 2004 (Box 586, Folder 1)
    - Fraternal Order of Police, 2003-2004 (Box 586, Folder 2)
    - Freedom Republicans, 1993 (Box 586, Folder 3)
    - Giles fix, 2004 (Box 586, Folder 4)
    - Gold Train, 2004 (Box 586, Folder 5)
    - Al Gore, 1997-1998 (Box 586, Folder 6)
    - Guns, 2001-2003 (Box 586, Folder 7)
    - Guns, 2004 (Box 586, Folder 8)
    - Haitian refugees, 2002-2003 (Box 586, Folder 9)
    - Hate crimes, 2003 (Box 586, Folder 10)
    - Health insurance, 2000-2003 (Box 586, Folder 11)
    - Health markets, 2000-2003 (Box 586, Folder 12)
    - Hearing, Prosecuting Iraqi war crimes, 2003 (Box 586, Folder 13)
    - High-risk nonprofits, 2004 (Box 586, Folder 14)
    - Houses of worship, 2003 (Box 586, Folder 15)
    - Human rights, 2003 (Box 586, Folder 16)
    - Independence Blue Cross, 2001-2004 (Box 586, Folder 17-18)
    - Independent judgement, 2004 (Box 586, Folder 19)
    - Intellectual property, 2003-2004 (Box 586, Folder 20)
    - Intellectual property, 2004 (Box 586, Folder 21)
    - Iraq loans, 2003-2004 (Box 586, Folder 22)
    - Iraq Resolution, 2003-2004 (Box 587, Folder 1)
    - Jewish affairs, 1998 (Box 587, Folder 2)
    - Judges, 2002-2003 (Box 587, Folder 3)
    - Judicial misconduct, 2003 (Box 587, Folder 4)
    - Judiciary, 1997-1998 (Box 587, Folder 5)
    - Judiciary, 1999 (Box 587, Folder 6)
    - Judiciary, 2001-2003 (Box 587, Folder 7)
    - Judiciary, DOJ oversight, 1997-1999 (Box 587, Folder 8)
    - Judiciary, DOJ oversight, Campaign finance, 1997-1998 (Box 587, Folder 9)
    - Judiciary, DOJ oversight, Independent counsel, 1997-1999 (Box 587, Folder 10)
    - Judiciary, DOJ oversight, Task force, 1999 (Box 587, Folder 11)
    - Judiciary, DOJ oversight, Transcripts, Johnny Chung, Charlie Trie, 1998-1999 (Box 587, Folder 12)
    - Judiciary, DOJ oversight, Transcripts, Committee on the Judiciary, 1999 (Box 587, Folder 13)
    - Judiciary, DOJ oversight, Transcripts, Hate crimes, 1999 (Box 587, Folder 14)
    - Judiciary, DOJ oversight, Peter H. Lee, Johnny Chung, Charlie Trie, John Huang, 1999 (Box 587, Folder 15)
    - Judiciary, Judicial nominations, 1998-2000 (Box 587, Folder 16)
    - Judiciary, Judicial nominations, 2003 (Box 588, Folder 1)
    - Judiciary, Judicial nominations, 2003-2004 (Box 588, Folder 2)
    - Judiciary, Judicial nominations, Janice Rodgers Brown, 2003 (Box 588, Folder 3)
    - Judiciary, Judicial nominations, Michael Fisher, 2003 (Box 588, Folder 4)
    - Judiciary, Judicial nominations, Michael Fisher, Opposition, 2003 (Box 588, Folder 5-6)
    - Judiciary, Judicial nominations, Frederica Massiah-Jackson, 1998 (Box 588, Folder 7)
    - Judiciary, Judicial nominations, William Pryor, 2003 (Box 588, Folder 8-11)
    - Judiciary, Judicial nominations, Franklin Van Antwerpen, 2004 (Box 588, Folder 12)
    - Judiciary, Judicial protocol, 2003-2004 (Box 588, Folder 13)
    - Judiciary, Juvenile justice (Box 588, Folder 14)
    - Judiciary, Juvenile justice, Publications, 1995-1996 (Box 588, Folder 15-16)
    - Judiciary, Testimony transcripts, 1999 (Box 588, Folder 17)
    - Judiciary, Subcommittee on Youth Violence testimonies, 1996 (Box 588, Folder 18)
    - Lao/Hmong Combat Veterans Naturalization Act, 1999 (Box 589, Folder 1)
    - Law Enforcement Officers Due Process Act, 2000 (Box 589, Folder 2)
    - Legal, 1999-2002 (Box 589, Folder 3-5)
    - Legislative, 1998-2001 (Box 589, Folder 6)
    - Legislative accomplishments, 1996 (Box 589, Folder 7)
    - Libya, 2003-2004 (Box 589, Folder 8)
    - Magistrate judges, 2004 (Box 589, Folder 9)
    - Medical College of Pennsylvania, 2004 (Box 589, Folder 10)
    - Medical malpractice, 2003-2004 (Box 589, Folder 11)
    - Middle East letters, 2003 (Box 589, Folder 12)
    - Military tribunals, 2001-2003 (Box 589, Folder 13)
    - Miscellaneous, 1996-2000 (Box 589, Folder 14-15)
    - Mahathir Mohamad, 2003 (Box 589, Folder 16)
    - Moldova, 2003 (Box 589, Folder 17)
    - Music Licensing Reform Act, 1996 (Box 589, Folder 18)
    - National Information Infrastructure (NII), Background, 1995-1996 (Box 589, Folder 19-20)
    - NII Copyright Protection Act, 1995-1996 (Box 589, Folder 21)
    - National security, 1996-1997 (Box 589, Folder 22)
    - National security, Clipper Chip, 1994-1995 (Box 589, Folder 23)
    - National security, Clipper Chip, 1994-1995 (Box 590, Folder 1)
    - National security, Espionage, 1994-2001 (Box 590, Folder 2)
    - National security, Foreign affairs and FBI, 1999-2000 (Box 590, Folder 3)
    - National security, Gun control, 1998-1999 (Box 590, Folder 4)
    - National security, The Militia Movement in the US hearing, 1995 (Box 590, Folder 5)
    - National security, Palestine Liberation Organization, 1996 (Box 590, Folder 6)
    - National security, Terrorism, Militia research, 1992-1995 (Box 590, Folder 7)
    - National security, Terrorism, Militias, 1995 (Box 590, Folder 8)
    - New nominations process (Box 590, Folder 9)
    - News clips, 1997-1999 (Box 590, Folder 10)
    - Nominating Commission, 2002-2003 (Box 590, Folder 11)
    - Office files, 1996-1999 (Box 590, Folder 12)
    - Oil for Food, 2004 (Box 590, Folder 13)
    - Omnibus Patent Act, 1996 (Box 590, Folder 14)
    - Organization of Petroleum Exporting Countries (OPEC), 2001-2004 (Box 590, Folder 15-16)
    - Padilla, 2003 (Box 590, Folder 17)
    - Pardons, 2001 (Box 590, Folder 18)
    - Pardons, Committee on the Judiciary hearing, 2001 (Box 590, Folder 19)
    - Pardons, Newsclips, 2001 (Box 590, Folder 20)
    - Pardons, Scholarly analyses, 2001 (Box 590, Folder 21)
    - Peer-to-peer networks, 2003 (Box 590, Folder 22)
    - Pennsylvania incitement, 2003 (Box 591, Folder 1)
    - Playwrights, 2004 (Box 591, Folder 2)
    - Police Corps, 2003 (Box 591, Folder 3)
    - Polygraph, Background, 2001 (Box 591, Folder 4-5)
    - Polygraph, Cases, 2001 (Box 591, Folder 6)
    - Polygraph, Hearing, 2001 (Box 591, Folder 7-8)
    - Polygraph, Statements and memos, 2001 (Box 591, Folder 9)
    - Post-9/11 bills, 2003 (Box 591, Folder 10)
    - Public Safety Officers Benefits Program, 2004 (Box 591, Folder 11)
    - Public Safety Officers Educational Assistance Act, 1998 (Box 591, Folder 12)
    - Punitive damages, 2003 (Box 591, Folder 13)
    - Questionnaires, 2003-2004 (Box 591, Folder 14)
    - Racial profiling, 2004 (Box 591, Folder 15)
    - Refugees, 1995-1999 (Box 591, Folder 16)
    - Republican Attorneys General Association, 1999-2003 (Box 591, Folder 17-18)
    - Road map for peace, 2003 (Box 591, Folder 19)
    - Ruby Ridge follow-up, 1997 (Box 591, Folder 20)